Guide to the Henry Seidel Canby Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1879-58; Series III; 12; (19 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - Turn West, Turn East: Mark Twain and Henry James
      - Draft A
        - Chapter 10, "Henry James: Casualty in Fiction; Calamity on the Stage": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 489)
        - Chapter 11, "Henry James: In Love with Technique": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 490)
        - Chapter 12, "The American Way": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 491)
        - Chapter 13, "Decline and Fall: Mark Twain"
          - Draft 1, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 492)
          - Draft 2, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 493)
          - Draft 3, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 494)
          - Draft 4, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 495)
        - Chapter 14, "Henry James: The Climax"
          - Draft 1, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 496)
          - Draft 2, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 497)
        - Chapter 15, "The American Scene": holograph, corrected [not published], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 498)
        - Chapter 16, "Decline and Disillusion of Henry James"
          - Draft 1, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 499)
          - Draft 2, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 500)
        - Chapter 17, "Conclusion": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 501)
        - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 502-503)
      - Draft B
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 504-510)
      - Draft fragments, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 511-514)
      - Advertisements, 1951 Nov (Box 24, Folder 515)
      - Book reviews, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 516-518)
    - Walt Whitman, An American
      - Research materials, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 519-524)
      - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 525-534)
      - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 535-537)
      - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 538-547)
      - Sample title page, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 548)
      - Dust jacket
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 915
      - Advertisements
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 916
      - Book reviews, 1943-44, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 549-550)
    - War Aims and Peace Ideals
      - Book reviews, 1919 May 22 (Box 26, Folder 551)
    - The Works of Thoreau
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 552)
      - Book reviews, 1937, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 553)
    - Unidentified book
      - Holograph and typescript draft (Box 27, Folder 554-557)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles, Essays, Speeches
      - [Abstract of an address made by Henry Seidel Canby at Union College:] typescript, with annotations, 1938 Sep 19 (Box 28, Folder 558)
      - "Admiring Descendant Sums Up Quaker Belief"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, ca. 1953 (Box 28, Folder 559)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1953 (Box 28, Folder 560-561)
        - Life: printed version, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 562)
      - "An Aided Courtship": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 563)
      - "The American Mind": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 28, Folder 564)
      - "The American Scholar and the War": brochure (Box 28, Folder 565)
      - "Amici Usque," The Prologue, A Pamphlet: pamphlet with copyright certificate, 1902 (Box 28, Folder 566)
      - "Anon Is Dead," The American Mercury: page proofs, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 567)
      - "Another Worst Book": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 568)
      - Bacon, Leonard (eulogy): draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 569)
      - "Betty's Ride: A Tale of the Revolution": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 28, Folder 570)
      - "Book Reviewing": printed version, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 571)
      - "Books and Civilization": draft, typescript (Box 28, Folder 572)
      - "Books That Are Milestones," Atlantic Monthly: offprint, 1951 Jun (Box 28, Folder 573)
      - "Bramwell Goes Fishing"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 574)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 575)
        - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 576)
      - "The Captured Hessian," Storytelling-- Narration: printed version, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 577)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 917
      - "Clear Thinking in Cloudy Times," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 578)
      - "Congreve As Dramatist," The Sewanee Review: printed version, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 579)
      - "Congreve As a Romanticist," PMLA: offprint, 2 copies, 1916 (Box 28, Folder 580)
      - "The Congrevians": draft, typescript, corrected, ca. 1913 (Box 28, Folder 581)
      - "Conrad and Melville," The Literary Review: printed version
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 918
      - "Cuatro Estodos de la Costa Atlántica": printed version
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 919
      - "Cupid and Psyche: A Study of a Fairy Tale": draft, typescript, corrected, 1913 (Box 28, Folder 582)
      - "The English Fabliau," PLMA: offprint, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 583)
      - "The First Crusade": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 584)
      - "The 'Fourth' In Our Town": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 28, Folder 585)
      - "The Fourth of July": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 586)
      - "Franklin Delano Roosevelt": draft, typescript, mimeograph (Box 28, Folder 587)
      - "Friends (Quakers) in Prison Reform," typescript (Box 28, Folder 588)
      - "Friendship": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 589)
      - "Gold": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 590)
      - "The Golden Age of Travel": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 591)
      - "The Good Old Days": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 592)
      - "Harper's Magazine -- A National Institution"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 593)
        - Galley proofs, 1925 Apr 22 (Box 28, Folder 594)
      - "Henry Seidel Canby," The Nation: printed version, 1924 Oct 8 (Box 28, Folder 595)
      - "Hindu Influence In American Thought": printed version, photocopy
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 920
      - "The History of Base Ball": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 596)
      - "Honest Questions Answered": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 597)
      - "Hobbs the Grind": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 28, Folder 598)
      - "In Burton Street": draft, typescript, corrected, 1916 Jul 31 (Box 28, Folder 599)
      - "In the Good Old Summer Time: About 1890"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 600)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 601)
      - "In this Fire of Love...": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 602)
      - "Literary Activity," Yale Daily News: printed version, 1915 Feb 22 (Box 28, Folder 603)
      - [Lounsberry, Eulogy for Professor:] printed version, 1915 Apr 12 (Box 28, Folder 604)
      - Mister Blandings Builds his Dream House, by Eric Hodgins, book club review by Henry Seidel Canby, offprint (Box 28, Folder 605)
      - "The Most Unforgettable Character I've Met"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 606)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 607)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, with printer's annotations, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 608)
          With: TLS from The Reader's Digest to Henry Seidel Canby, 1942 May 7
      - "Nature and Literary Tradition in America": draft, holograph, corrected, 1915 Dec 13 (Box 28, Folder 609)
      - "A New Land Speaking": draft, holograph, corrected (incomplete) (Box 28, Folder 610)
      - "On Dramatic Prudery": draft, typescript (Box 28, Folder 611)
      - "On Reading Poetry": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 612)
      - "On the Tennessee Trail": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 613)
      - "Oscar Wilde": draft, holograph, corrected, 1915 Apr (Box 28, Folder 614)
      - "Peace On Earth and How to Get It": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 29, Folder 615)
      - "Poe and Hawthorne": draft, holograph, corrected (with program), 1918 Jul (Box 29, Folder 616)
      - "The Post and Its Literary Review," The New York Post: printed version, 1943 Oct 7 (Box 29, Folder 617)
      - "The Price We Pay for 'Latin and Greek'": draft, typescript (Box 29, Folder 618)
      - "The Race of Reviewers," The Nation: printed version, 1921 Jun 22 (Box 29, Folder 619)
      - "Remarks on Reviewing," Current Literature: printed version, 1930 Feb 3-7 (Box 29, Folder 620)
      - "Review of November Lit.," Yale Daily News: printed version, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 621)
      - "The Reviewing of Books," The Atlantic Monthly: printed version, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 622)
      - "Rule of a Nation by a Nation" [Ireland]: draft, typescript (Box 29, Folder 623)
      - "Seeing America Last"
        - Draft A, typescript, with holograph pages, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 624)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 625)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 626)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 627)
      - "Sentimentalism and American Literature": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 29, Folder 628)
      - "Shall We 'Give Up' Ireland": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 29, Folder 629)
      - "The Short Story": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 630)
      - "The Short Story": pamphlet, 2 c., 1902 (Box 29, Folder 631)
      - "Some Comments on the Sources of Chaucer's 'Pardoner's Tale'": offprint, 1905 Apr (Box 29, Folder 632)
      - "Speech at Anglo-Saxon Fellowship Meeting, Central Hall, Westminster"
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, 1918 Jul 4 (Box 29, Folder 633)
          See also: Box 39, folder 908
        - Program, 1918 Jul 4 (Box 29, Folder 634)
      - "A Study of Chaucer's Method of Narrative": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 635)
      - "Sunday at Music Mountain": printed version (Box 29, Folder 636)
      - "Talk to Wounded at Cliveden": draft, holograph, corrected, ca. 1918 (Box 29, Folder 637)
      - "There Are Two American Traditions: Which Is Yours?": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 638)
      - [Thoreau, Henry David, Essay on:] draft, typescript, carbon (Box 29, Folder 639)
      - "Through All Persons I Will Woo Thee": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 640)
      - "Town Meeting" [Killingworth, Conn.]: draft, typescript, corrected (Box 29, Folder 641)
      - "The Underplot": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 29, Folder 642)
      - "U. S. Literature In This Century" [in Portuguese]: typescript, mimeograph, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 643)
        With: TLS from the Department of State. Special Events Unit. International Broadcasting Division, to Henry Seidel Canby, 1947 May 21.
      - "War or Peace in Literature," The Saturday Review of Literature: offprint, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 644)
      - "Weekend On the Concord and Merrimac Rivers": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 29, Folder 645)
      - "What Do You Want?," This Week: printed version, 1948 Jan 4 (Box 29, Folder 646)
      - "What Do You Want For Christmas?": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 647)
      - "What Is a Liberal?"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 648)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 649)
      - "What Is English?," The English Journal: offprint, 1920 Sep (Box 29, Folder 650)
      - "The World Forgetting": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 651)
      - "Writing English," Harper's Monthly Magazine: printed version (Box 29, Folder 652)
      - Unidentified essay, re [Thomas Seal], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 653)
      - Unidentified essay, American fiction, draft, typescript, carbon (Box 29, Folder 654)
      - Unidentified essay, re Waynesville, North Carolina, draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 655)
      - Unidentified lecture on the Irish Question, draft, typescript, ca. 1918 (Box 29, Folder 656)
      - Unidentified radio broadcast, re Long, Long Ago, by Alexander Woolcott, and The Apostle, by Sholem Asch, draft, typescript, corrected, 1943 Nov 28 (Box 29, Folder 657)
      - Unidentified radio broadcast re Australian culture, draft, typescript, corrected, 1945 May 6 (Box 29, Folder 658)
      - Unidentified radio broadcast re Australian culture, draft, typescript, carbon, 1945 May 13 (Box 29, Folder 659)
      - Unidentified draft fragments, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 660-661)
      - Miscellaneous research notes, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 662-664)
      - Printed materials concerning Canby's
        - Articles and essays, 1914-26, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 665)
      - Public lectures, speeches, and addresses
        - General, 1919-40, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 666)
        - Australia-New Zealand lecture tour, 1945-46 (Box 30, Folder 667)
    - Book Reviews
      - Cross, Wilbur L., Connecticut Yankee: An Autobiography: printed version, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 668)
      - Dark, Eleanor, The Little Company: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 669)
      - Foerster, Norman, ed., The Reinterpretation of American Literature: offprint, 1929 Mar 2 (Box 30, Folder 670)
      - Fontaine, Robert, The Happy Time: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 671)
      - Forester, C. S., Commodore Hornblower: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 672)
      - Gorman, Herbert S., The Wine of San Lorenzo: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 673)
      - Hudson, W. H., A Traveller In Little Things: draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 30, Folder 674)
      - Kravchenko, Victor, I Choose Freedom: draft, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 30, Folder 675)
      - Langley, Adria Locke, A Lion Is In the Streets: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 676)
      - Lawrence, T. E., The Mint: printed version, 1936 Dec 14 (Box 30, Folder 677)
      - Marquand, John P., H. M. Pulham, Esquire: printed version (Box 30, Folder 678)
      - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinnan, Cross Creek: printed version, 2 c., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 679)
      - Shaw, George Bernard, Saint Joan: printed version, photocopy, 1924 Aug 2 (Box 30, Folder 680)
      - Stevenson, Elizabeth, Henry James: Man of Imagination: draft, typescript (Box 30, Folder 681)
      - Thoreau, Henry David, The Modern Thoreau: printed version, 1915 Jul 15 (Box 30, Folder 682)
      - Wells, H. G., The Outline of History: printed version, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 683)
      - White, Vaughan, Our Neighbours: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 684)
    - Letters to the Editor
      - Herald: typescript, original, 1946 Oct 16 (Box 30, Folder 685)
      - Journal Courier: typescript, carbon, 1918 Dec 17 (Box 30, Folder 686)
      - The Nation: printed version, 1910 Nov 3 (Box 30, Folder 687)
      - The New Republic: draft, typescript, carbon, 1917 Apr 17 (Box 30, Folder 688)
      - The New York Evening Post
        - Printed version, 1917 Oct 13 (Box 30, Folder 689)
        - Printed version, 1919 Oct 1 (Box 30, Folder 690)
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 691)
      - The New York Herald Tribune
        - Printed version (multiple signatories), 1943 Jul 3 (Box 30, Folder 692)
        - Printed version, 1947 May 9 (Box 30, Folder 693)
      - The New York Times: draft, holograph, corrected, ca. 1940 (Box 30, Folder 694)
      - The Yale Alumni Weekly
        - Typescript, original, 1909 Apr 2 (Box 30, Folder 695)
        - Printed version, fragment, 1927 Dec 16 (Box 30, Folder 696)
      - Yale Daily News
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, 1918 Apr (Box 30, Folder 697)
        - Printed version, 1918 Apr 17 (Box 30, Folder 698)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Bacon, Leonard: "An Ode for the Two Hundred and Fiftieth Anniversary of the Founding of Yale College": printed version, 1951 Oct 19 (Box 30, Folder 699)
    - Barker, Virgil: Cubism and Abstract Art...: published by the Museum of Modern Art, book review, typescript, original, corrected (Box 30, Folder 700)
    - Bell, Bernard Iddings: God and His Troubled World by W. R. Matthews: book review, holograph, corrected, signed (Box 30, Folder 701)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent: Western Star: second copy, typescript, corrected, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 702-706)
    - Blunden, Edmund: "The Tune": holograph, signed (Box 30, Folder 707)
    - Bogarty, Simon: Blight: The Tragedy of Dublin (An Exposition in 3 Acts): printed version, 1917 (Box 30, Folder 708)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck: untitled autograph ms., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 709)
    - Brownell, W. C.: "Poe," printed version, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 710)
    - [B., Z.,:] untitled poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 711)
    - C., C. M.: "Petunias, 1840," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 712)
      With: note from C. M. C. to Henry [Seidel Canby], n.d.
    - Canby, Marion
      - "Hendy Caps," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 31, Folder 713)
      - High Mowing (collection of poetry): book review, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 714)
      - Poems ("Come No Nearer!", "Rough Work", and "Sea-Marsh: South Carolina"): printed version, 1929-31 (Box 31, Folder 715)
    - Chamberlin, John
      - Farewell to Reform; contract, 1932 Mar 11 (Box 31, Folder 716)
        With: bill, 1933 Jul 31
      - "Paradox of the Muck-Raker:" review of The Letters of Lincoln Steffens, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 717)
    - Cowley, Malcolm: letter to the editor, Herald Tribune Books: printed version, 1924 Oct 26 (Box 31, Folder 718)
    - Davison, Edward: "Beauty for Ashes": autograph ms. in the hand of Frank Kendon (Box 31, Folder 719)
    - DeVoto, Bernard: "The River," movie review, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 720)
    - Dodd, Lee Wilson
      - "A Draft of XXX Cantos," printed version, 1933 May 20 (Box 31, Folder 721)
      - "Internal" holograph, signed, n.d.
      - "Moonshine. After Verlaine," holograph, signed, 1902 Apr
      - "Pastel in Prose...": holograph, n.d.
      - "Response on Receiving the Tower's Honorary Degree," printed version, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 722)
      - "To-": holograph, signed, 1913 Sep 6
      - "To H. S. C.": holograph, signed, 1907 Jun 15 (Box 31, Folder 723)
        With: ANS to Henry Seidel Canby from Lee Wilson Dodd, n.d.
      - Untitled poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 724)
    - Frank, William P.
      - "In Witness Whereof".... typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 725)
    - Gause, Helen Louise
      - "The Honey Bee" (poem): draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 726)
      - Untitled poem, holograph, 1897 Sep 28 (Box 31, Folder 727)
    - Hazlitt, Henry: "Out Greatest Authors: How Great Are They?," The Forum: printed version, 1932 Oct (Box 31, Folder 728)
    - Hill, Helen: Is Germany Finished? by Pierre Vienot; The Germans... by George N. Shuster; and The German Crisis by H. Knickerbocker: book reviews, typescript, original, signed (Box 31, Folder 729)
    - Hooker, W. B.: "Morning at the Club" (poem): draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 730)
    - Hougland, Willard, ed.: "Mary Austin: A Memorial:" pamphlet, 1944 Sep (Box 31, Folder 731)
    - Kendall, Alice G.: "The Short Story in the Mid-Century Magazine, autograph ms., 1911 Apr 5 (Box 31, Folder 732)
    - Knopf, Alfred A.: "Joseph Conrad: The Romance of His Life and of His Books:" pamphlet, ca. 1913 (Box 31, Folder 733)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood: "A Kind of Pantheism:" printed version, 1950 Jun 10 (Box 31, Folder 734)
    - Leisy, Ernest E.: "Materials for Investigations in American Literature": offprint, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 735)
    - Lindsay, Nicholas Vachel: "The Gospel of Beauty": printed version (Box 31, Folder 736)
    - Lovett, Robert Morss: "The Beginning of the Short Story in America": printed version, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 737)
    - McCord, David: "Round the Gaspé": type- script, original, corrected (Box 31, Folder 738)
    - Matthiessen, F. O.: "To the Memory of Phelps Putnam": offprint, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 739)
    - Mencken, H. L.: letter to the editor: printed version, ca. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 740)
    - Moore, Guy G.: Letter to the Editor of The Saturday Review: typescript, 1936 Jan 16 (Box 31, Folder 741)
    - Morley, Christopher
      - "Heywood" [eulogy for Heywood Broun]: pamphlet, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 742)
      - "A Love Story": printed version, 1923 Dec 31
      - Untitled poem: holograph, n.d.
    - Morley, Felix: Undiscovered Australia by Sir G. H. Watkins, book reviews, holograph (Box 31, Folder 743)
    - "O. Henry and the Popular Short Story" [anonymous review of O. Henry's Whirligigs ]: printed version (Box 31, Folder 744)
    - [O'Neill, George:] "Story": typescript, signed, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 745)
    - Oppenheimer, Franz M.: "Lament for Unbought Grace: The Novels of John P. Marquand": offprint, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 746)
    - Piérud, Louis
      - "A history of the Flemish movement": holograph, signed, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 747)
      - "Belgian art in America": holograph, signed, n.d.
      - "Verhaeren's House and Tomb": holograph, signed
        With: ALS to Henry Seidel Canby from Louis Piérud, 1929 Sep 29
    - [Randall?]: "Ainsworth's Magazine for 1852, Vol. XXI:" review, autograph ms., 1911 Apr 5 (Box 31, Folder 748)
    - Santayana, George: "Tom Sawyer and Don Quixote," Mark Twain Quarterly: printed version (Box 31, Folder 749)
    - Siordet, Gerald Caldwell
      - "To the Dead:" printed version, 1915 Nov 30 (Box 31, Folder 750)
      - Untitled poem: autograph ms., [ca. 1912]
        With: note from Henry [Seidel Canby] to "Charles"
    - Smith, Logan Pearsall: "Fine Writing:" offprint, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 751)
    - Speakman, Abigail: "Phebe Thomas- Grandmother": typescript, carbon (Box 31, Folder 752)
    - Symons, Arthur: "Hawthorne," The Lamp: printed version, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 753)
    - Tolles, Frederick B.: "Emerson and Quakerism," American Literature: printed version (Box 31, Folder 754)
    - Untermeyer, Louis
      - Bringing Jazz: by Max Bodenheim, book review, holograph, signed, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 755)
      - "The Less Shakespeare He": book review, holograph, signed, n.d.
      - Peeps at Parnassus: by Olga Katzin, holograph, signed, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 756)
      - "Verse": book review, holograph, n.d.
    - Walsh, Joseph: "To Walter Savage Landor": [holograph], 1928 Nov 1 (Box 31, Folder 757)
    - Ward, C. H.: "The Humble Petition": [holograph], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 758)
    - Welty, Eudora: "The Reading and Writing of Short Stories," Atlantic: printed version (Box 31, Folder 759)
    - White, Sir Frederick: The Cambridge History of the British Empire, Vol. V: The Indian Empire: review, autograph ms. (Box 31, Folder 760)
    - Whitman, Walt: Two Prefaces, with "Introductory Note" by Christopher Morley: page proofs. With an inscription from Christopher Morley to Henry Seidel Canby, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 761)
    - Unidentified
      - "Foo," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 762)
      - "Funiculi--Funicula," typescript, in Italian, n.d.
      - "Half Slave, Half Free," printed version, 1921 May 26 (Box 31, Folder 763)
      - "How Canidates Sound and Read," printed version, 1920
      - "Lines written in dejection on the Philadelphia," typescript (Box 31, Folder 764)
      - "Margarita," typescript, carbon, in Italian, n.d.
      - "The Neglected Book," printed version, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 765)
      - "New York Weather," printed version, 1921
      - "Oje Cauli," typescript, carbon, in Italian, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 766)
      - "On Babe Bunting," printed version, n.d.
      - "Open Spaces in New York," printed version, n.d.
      - "Santa Lucia," autograph ms., in Italian, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 767)
      - "A Sunday morning on a Kansas farm," typescript